publicrecordspro.com 2017-11-07

# Privacy Policy | PeopleSmart

##  What is covered by this privacy policy? 

This privacy policy covers PeopleSmart.com, which is designed to help you find public records information about yourself and others. This site is not a consumer-reporting agency as defined by the [Fair Credit Reporting Act](https://www.peoplesmart.com/fcra) (FCRA). Visit [GoodHire.com](https://www.goodhire.com/gh.aspx?_act=landing&cam=6336) for all your employment screening needs. 

##  What isn’t covered by this policy? 

This privacy policy only applies to information collected by this website, which is owned and operated by Inflection.com, Inc. This policy does not apply to the practices of other website domains that this site links to, to other Inflection services, to the practices of companies that we do not own or control, or to people that we do not employ or manage. 

If you want to submit an opt-out request to remove yourself from the search results of this and other people search sites we operate, please click here. We will try our best to honor it. 

If you choose to opt out of search results, that choice may affect the visibility of the relevant information on our entire network of sites, which includes this website, Identity.com, and other affiliated properties. We try our best to honor your request, but our opt-out system is not perfect and it may miss records that don’t perfectly match the information you submit. 

##  Your Public Records Exist Elsewhere In The World – We Do Not Control Them 

This site displays public records that are available in the real world, such as criminal history records from law enforcement agencies and bankruptcy records from courts. Original copies of public records can only be changed by those entities. Inflection obtains its public records through third party sources. Please note that exercising the opt-out option will not actually delete or change the original copies of such records. 

**Note:** If you consent to the release of your information via another Inflection product or service (e.g., a background report on GoodHire.com), your public records will be shared for the purpose you specify. 

##  User Data Supplementation 

We may receive information about you from other sources, including publicly available databases or third parties from whom we have purchased data, and combine this data with information we already have about you. This helps us to update, expand and analyze our records, identify new customers, and provide products and services that may be of interest to you. If you provide us personal information about others, or if others give us your information, we will only use that information for the specific reason for which it was provided to us. Please see the “What This Policy Covers”. 

##  Your safety and privacy are very important to us 

We want to minimize the risk of harm resulting from use of public records information. Please contact us if you are particularly at risk for certain types of harm as a result of your public records being available on this site. Inflection will work with you on mitigating the risk of any potential harm, including physical harm, threats to public officials such as law enforcement, and issues related to identity theft. Please send your request to our Privacy Department at [privacy@peoplesmart.com](mailto:privacy@peoplesmart.com) along with appropriate documentation or call us at 1-888-906-4278. 

##  We Collect Information Related to Your Account and Identity 

Registration is optional on this site. Registering makes certain features available to you. When you register for an account, we may collect the following information from you: 

  * Your name, email address, mailing address, and phone number
  * Username and password
  * Communications related to customer service requests

##  We Collect Information Necessary for Payments and Other Products 

If you choose to purchase a report or subscription on this site, we may collect and retain information to complete the purchase and prevent fraud. 

You can buy reports on this service by entering your payment information, including your credit card information, name, email address, and physical address. For processing payments, we use systems that are compliant with the Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard (PCI DSS). All payment and transaction-related information is safely stored according to PCI DSS requirements. 

If you choose to use one of our communication relay services (for example, our email relay or postal relay services), we will collect your message content, as well as your relevant contact information for return correspondence. Please note that your contact information (e.g. name and email address or name and mailing address) will be shared with the person you contact through the relay service. 

##  Information We Collect From All Visitors 

###  Technical and Analytics Information 

We collect technical and analytics information from all visitors. This information includes your IP address, the URL that brought you to the site, and information about your device and browser. 

###  Activity Information 

When you visit this site, we may collect information about which pages you visit, who and what you search for, and the products you buy. 

###  Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies 

This site makes use of tools such as cookies to collect various types of information about your activity and computer while you use the website. We only use information collected in the background to deliver and market our service - _information collected by cookies and other tools is not used to augment our search results_. 

The methods we use to collect technical and analytics data include the following: 

  * We use cookies and similar technologies, and our partners may, too. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the website, tracking users’ movements around the site, and gathering demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual and aggregated basis. You can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level, but if you choose to disable cookies, it may limit your use of certain features or functions on our website or service. To manage Flash cookies, please click [here](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html):
  * Technologies such as: cookies, beacons, tags and scripts are used by Inflection.com, Inc., our affiliates, and our analytics and service providers. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking your movements around the site, and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by our service providers on an individual as well as aggregated basis.
  * We use cookies for our shopping cart, to remember your settings (e.g. language preference), for authentication, and for analyzing site usage. You can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some features or areas of our site may be limited.
  * As is true of most web sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information may include your internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or your clickstream data. We may combine this automatically collected log information with other information we collect about you. We do this to improve the services we offer you, to improve marketing, analytics, and site functionality.
  * We partner with third parties to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third-party partners may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on this site and other sites in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads, you may opt-out by clicking [here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/). If you are located in the European Union, please click [here](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/). Please note this does not opt you out of being served ads. You will continue to receive generic ads. To learn more about these practices, and about how to opt out of certain advertising, you can visit the [Google opt-out page](http://www.google.com/ads/preferences/), and the Network Advertising Initiative’s [opt-out system](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/). For a closer look into the third-party advertising and tracking cookies we use, you can consult our [About Our Cookies page](https://www.peoplesmart.com/about-our-cookies). This privacy resource provides useful information and options for opting out of these cookies. 
  * Third parties with whom we partner to provide certain features on our site or to display advertising based upon your Web browsing activity use LSOs such as HTML 5 to collect and store information.
  * Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing content stored locally using HTML5.
  * **Third Party Analytics**. We have engaged Inspectlet to analyse the activities of visitors to this website, and Inspectlet’s authorized use of cookies and other tracking technologies enable it to have access to Personal Information of visitors to this website. Such access to and use of Personal Information by Inspectlet is governed by Inspectlet’s Privacy Policy [[https://www.inspectlet.com/legal#privacy]](https://www.inspectlet.com/legal#privacy).
  * **Social media integration**. The site includes social media features operated by third parties, such as the Facebook Like button. These features may collect your IP address and other information about your browsing activity, including the page you are visiting on our site. The information those services collect is subject to their respective privacy policies.

##  How We Use The Information We Collect 

Your information is only used to provide and market this service for visitors and registered users, which includes operating the website, remembering your preferences, conducting in-house research, preventing fraud or abuse, marketing to you products or services offered by us, and to communicate with you and address your concerns. 

##  We Only Share Your Information in the Following Situations 

**With Your Consent:** We may share your information when you give us permission. 

**With Our Parent Company:** Inflection.com, Inc. owns a variety of products and services in addition to this site, including Identity.com, GoodHire.com, PeopleSmart.com, and other people search sites. Data collected under this privacy policy is shared with Inflection and stored alongside data from those other services. Your choices on one service may affect another service – for instance, opting out on PeopleSmart.com may mean that your records will not be available on Identity.com. 

**With Service Providers:** We use certain trusted third parties to provide services for us such as payments processing. We only share the minimum amount of information necessary to provide the service. In addition, any third-party service provider we use is required to give your information the same protections that are outlined here in this Privacy Policy. 

**Deidentified and Aggregated Data:** We may share or disclose information we collect after deidentifying and aggregating it so it cannot be linked back to an individual person. We contractually require third parties to respect this practice. 

**Business Transfers:** In the event that Inflection is involved in a bankruptcy, merger, acquisition, reorganization or sale of assets, your information may be sold or transferred as part of that transaction. However, the new entity will be bound by this privacy policy after the sale or transfer. 

**Fraud and Abuse Prevention:** We partner with certain third party vendors to prevent fraud and abuse. When you make a purchase, we analyze your payment information and unique device identifiers (including, but not limited to, IP address, geographical location, browser and operating system settings) to identify suspected fraudulent activity and block it. We may share information associated with activity flagged as fraudulent (including, but not limited to, payment information, email addresses, and unique device identifiers) with our security partners or law enforcement for further investigation. 

**Legal Process and Emergency Circumstances:** In certain situations, we may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements. We may disclose or preserve for future disclosure your information if we believe, after due consideration, that doing so is reasonably necessary to protect Inflection’s rights or property or to comply with a law, regulation, valid legal process, or to prevent imminent and serious bodily harm to a person. 

If you are a law enforcement officer seeking information from Inflection about one of our users, please reference our [Law Enforcement Guidelines](https://www.inflection.com/privacy/additional-privacy-resources/law-enforcement-guide) for further information. 

Unless prohibited from doing so by law or court order, we will do our best to provide subjects of law enforcement requests with advance notice before we disclose their information to law enforcement, if we have contact information for that person. We reserve the right to withhold advance notice where it would impede an investigation of identity theft, or in situations involving imminent physical harm or harm to minors. 

##  How We Retain And Protect Your Information 

We may retain your information for as long as your account is active, or as needed to provide you services, comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes and enforce our agreements. .If you use your account to opt out of public record searches, we will do our best to suppress your records from our people search products, in accordance with our opt-out policy. 

Your information is stored on secure servers in Northern California. While we use acceptable industry-standard practices to protect your information, we cannot and do not guarantee that your information will be absolutely secure. Here are a few other steps we take to protect your information: 

  * We implement technical measures to prevent unauthorized access, and keep security patches and software up-to-date
  * Employee access to your information is restricted and audited
  * Sensitive personal information is stored in encrypted form
  * All personal information is encrypted during transfer (for example, when providing credit card information)

##  Choices And Other Privacy Information 

###  Access and corrections 

Upon request, we will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your personal information.

You may use your account to access, correct, or change any personal information you have provided to us or associated with your account. You may also email our Privacy Team at [privacy@peoplesmart.com](mailto:privacy@peoplesmart.com). We will do our best to promptly respond to your request. 

###  Deleting Your Account 

In the event you want to delete an account that you have created, which includes your customer registration information, please contact our Privacy Team at [privacy@peoplesmart.com](mailto:privacy@peoplesmart.com). For information about opting out of our public records search records, click here. We will do our best to promptly respond to your request. 

###  Communication Preferences 

We may send you information about our products, notices regarding your account, and other messages related to this and other services we own, including marketing emails. You can unsubscribe from commercial emails by clicking on the unsubscribe link in those emails, emailing [privacy@peoplesmart.com](mailto:privacy@peoplesmart.com) with the email address you wish to unsubscribe from, or by calling 1-888-906-4278. Please note that you may still receive account and billing notices from us, if applicable. 

###  Data Sources 

For information on data sources used by PeopleSmart.com, please visit the Data Sources Education page. 

##  Social Media Widgets 

Our website includes social media, such as the Facebook Like button, and widgets, such as the Share This button or interactive mini-programs that run on our website. These features may collect your Internet protocol address, which page you are visiting on our website, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social Media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our website. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy statement of the company providing it. 

##  California’s ‘Do Not Track’ law 

When you browse our website, we may use trusted third-party tools to analyze website usage, monitor performance, and prevent fraud. This site does not currently respond to browser settings such as Do Not Track. Third parties, such as our fraud prevention tools, may also collect personally identifiable information from you. 

##  California Information-Sharing Disclosure 

We do not share your personal information that you submit to us with third parties for direct marketing purposes without your permission. 

##  Children’s Information 

This site is not directed to individuals under the age of 13 and we do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13. If we discover that we have collected personal information on a child under the age of 13 via this site, we will promptly remove it from our systems. 

##  Changes to this Privacy Policy 

If we modify this Privacy Policy, we will notify you before the changes become effective. We encourage you to review this page periodically for the latest information about our privacy practices. 

##  Contact Information 

We are located at 555 Twin Dolphin Drive #200, Redwood City, CA 94065. If you have any questions or concerns regarding this policy, please contact us: 

Privacy Department   
P.O. Box 391146   
Omaha, NE 68139 

1-888-906-4278   

## TRUSTe

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) [here](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request). 

Effective Date Of This Policy: August 25, 2017
